Welcome back to Beijing, Mr. President.
Thanks for the time.
>> Thank you.
>> You know, you've said that this summit
is a success. As you get ready to head
back to Washington, what's the most
significant specific thing you walk away
from here for the US? I think the most
important thing is relationship. It's
all about relationship. I have a very
good relationship with President Xi and
with China. And it sounds like something
that doesn't mean anything, but it's
everything. in deal making and problems
we've solved. The two of us have solved
a lot of problems between that somebody
else would have maybe done very badly
with. We've solved a lot of problems
over the years. We have a very good
relationship. Uh trade has been very
strong. We're getting a lot of soybeans
for our farmers. We're doing a lot of uh
there's a lot of things happening with
for the farmers. He committed to 200
Boeings, big ones. 777s and 737s and a
lot of big uh big ones, big beautiful
Boeing planes. 200, that's a lot. Uh
with a commitment that if they do a good
job, and I told this to Boeing and
General Electric, we're going to go the
General Electric engines, which are
great. If they do a good job, we could
go up to 750.
>> And that's obviously a lot of investment
going back and forth. You know, some
Democrats, even some Republicans, had
some concerns about Chinese
manufacturing on US soil. Is that
happening?
>> Well, uh, if they don't want to pay
tariffs, it could happen, just like it's
happening with other countries and
companies. We have now more money being
invested in the United States than any
country at any time in the history of
the world, including China, which
probably is second from about 10 years
ago. We have $18 trillion in 11 months.
Not the 12th month hasn't come in yet,
the numbers. We have $18 trillion. If
China wants to come in and wants to
avoid tariffs, if they build here, for
the most part, they're going to be
hiring American people. If they want to
avoid tariffs, they're going to build in
the United States.
>> Despite my concerns about China
operating inside the US,
>> we have Japan is building massive
Toyota, Honda, all of them. I mean,
they're building massive plants all over
the country. So if China wants to build
for their cars, now I will tell you I
put a 100% tariff on Chinese cars
because I didn't want them coming into
the country. If you take a only because
they swamp you, they'll destroy your
auto industry. And that's what's
happening in Europe. And now they're
saying we have to do a little bit like
Donald Trump. Europe is being killed.
They're being absolutely swamped by
hundreds of thousands, millions of
Chinese cars and Mercedes and BMW and
Volkswagen. They're getting killed. So,
uh, if you notice, we haven't had that
problem. You know why? Because I have a
100% tariff on cars made in China.
>> And even though the Supreme Court
ruling, you're going to still continue
that tariff.
>> The ruling was just on a specific type
of tariff.
>> And you're going a different route.
>> Correct. I have the right to do the same
tariff in frankly a little bit more
complex way, but it's actually a better
tariff. It's actually it's a more
stringent tariff.
>> I want to ask you about Iran and AI, but
but China made clear that Taiwan is very
important to them. And after your first
meeting here, President Xi's spokesman
put out a statement to the media through
the media saying this. The Taiwan
question is the most important issue in
China US relations. If it is handled
properly, the bilateral relationship
will enjoy overall stability. Otherwise,
the two countries will have clashes and
even conflicts putting the entire
relationship in great jeopardy. You were
still inside the meeting when that came
out. That sounded almost like a threat.
Was it Was it communicated that way
behind closed doors?
>> No. And no, it wasn't not at all. But it
has always been their most important
issue. [snorts] And it's not a takeover.
They just don't want to see this uh
place called a place because nobody
knows how to define it. But they don't
want to see it go independent. They
don't want to do it. And uh I think they
probably would do something pretty harsh
and then they would be met harshly and
bad things will happen. Uh so no, it's
it's not that. It's we talked, by the
way, last night we talked a whole night
about that issue. I think um I know more
about Taiwan right now than I know about
almost any country.
>> He dominated the the talk.
>> It it it's always been his most
important thing from the day I knew him
years ago. I've known him now 11 years,
12 years. Uh it's always been the
biggest thing for him. Taiwan. Now with
me, I don't think they'll do anything
when I'm here. When I'm not here, I
think they might to be honest with you.
So, I'm not sure that they do anything
if it remained as is,
>> but they have somebody there now that
wants to go independent. Well, it's a
risky thing when you go independent. You
know, they're going independent because
they want to get into a war and they
want to they figure they have a United
States behind them. Uh, I'd like to see
it stay the way it is. And I'll tell you
something, I'll make a little news. I'd
like to see everybody making chips over
in Taiwan come into America because to
be honest with you, I think it's the
greatest thing you can do cuz it's a
heated situation. And there's no
question about it. And uh as you know,
we have massive amounts of chip
companies now from Taiwan already coming
in. We expect to have 40 to 50% of the
world chip business by the end of my
term. And uh I think it should be even
more than that. I think all of those
chip companies that if they're smart,
they're going to start heading to
Arizona and the places where they're
building. That's going to solve your
problem. Should the people of Taiwan
feel more or less secure after your
meetings with President Xi?
>> Uh, neutral. Neutral. This is
>> Has the policy changed at all?
>> No, nothing chang.
>> No, nothing's changed. I will say this.
I'm not looking to have somebody go
independent and, you know, we're
supposed to travel 9,500 miles to fight
a war. I'm not looking for that. Uh, I
want them to cool down. I want China to
cool down. But you're waiting on
approving billions of dollars of weapons
>> for Taiwan. Is that moving forward?
>> Well, I haven't approved it yet. We're
going to see what happens.
I may do it, I may not do it.
>> Yeah. What's your your hinge point?
>> Well, I'm not going to say that, but I
may do it. I may not do it. But we're
not looking to have wars. And we're if
you kept it the way it is, I think
China's going to be okay with that. But
we're not looking to have somebody say,
"Let's go independent because the United
States is backing us, you know." So,
President Xi probably liked that you
haven't approved the weapons to Taiwan.
>> Um, I would say like is maybe too strong
a word because he thinks I could do it
with just the signing of my signature
unlike Biden who couldn't sign his
signature. Um, no, I'm holding that in
obeyance and it depends on China.
Depends. It's it's a very good
negotiating chip for us, frankly.
It's a lot of weapons. It's 12 billion
dollars. It's a lot of weapons. But, you
know, when you look at the odds, China
is a very, very powerful big country.
That's a very small island. It's, you
think of it, it's 59 miles away. 59
miles. We're 9,500 miles away. Uh,
that's a little bit of a difficult
problem. With all of that uh being said,
you know, if you look at the history of
Taiwan, Taiwan was uh developed because
we had presidents that didn't know what
the hell they were doing because if they
would have put tariffs on chips coming
in, it would they would have never left.
Everything was about Intel and
everything was about our chip companies.
They stole our chip industry. So, I've
said that for years. I said, you know,
for years they stole our chip. If we
would have had one of our presidents
just say, "We're going to say going to
put 100% chip. You can leave. You can
build in Taiwan, but we're going to you
sell it back into the United States.
We're going to put 100% or 200% tariff."
We would have never lost a chip. We lost
the chip industry. It's all coming back.
And I do say this, uh,
Taiwan would be very smart to cool it a
little bit. China would be very smart to
cool it a little bit. They well both
cool it
>> on AI. Was there any agreement about any
kind of guard rails that China and the
US might agree to so that AI doesn't go
crazy and take
>> We talked about it. Yeah, we talked.
Look, AI is mostly a great thing. Mostly
uh and we're leading China. We talked
about that. We're leading China by a
lot. Um I gave the right for AI to build
their own electric producing plants.
That's a big deal. they can manufacture
their own electricity now which we could
never have gotten from the grid and that
and now you have these very rich
companies headed by lots of geniuses
building electric plants because of that
we are leading China by a lot in the AI
race now it's mostly the two of us other
nations are in it but mostly and whoever
wins the AI race and we're going to win
it I mean if we're smart we're going to
win it if we're not smart we're not but
we're leading by a lot we talked about
that last Tonight, President Xi was very
surprised at how well we've done with uh
AI because they thought, you know, when
it started, they they took this gigantic
lead and we now have caught we are
substantially ahead of them in AI.
>> But do you think there'll be some buyin,
set up guard rails or something?
>> I think there could be. We talked about
it, but you know, at the same time,
we're competing. So, it's a little hard
to say, "Oh, gee, let's put on we're
competing with each other and we're
going to put guardrails." It really
doesn't work that way too too much. Uh
but AI, if you look at medicine, some of
the things they're coming up with
medicine, some of the cures they're
coming up with that people would have
never gotten there, it's going to be
mostly a good thing, but we we want to
have some guardrails.
>> You said that the president Xi said he
would offer assistance on Iran and
specifically
>> I also said we don't need assistance.
>> You don't didn't ask for it. You said he
he was offering it specifically to open
the straight of war moves. What what do
you think he will do? I think he's been
very nice about it. He gets 40% of his
oil there. He didn't send anybody. He
didn't send ships. He didn't send ships
with big fat guns on them that we would
have had to repel. We would have.
The good thing is we're the I built
during my first four years the most
powerful military in the world. We have
the most powerful military in the world.
That was shown in Venezuela which took
one day. Actually took 48 hour. I mean
took let's see about 48 minutes. I think
it was 48 minutes and 13 seconds and it
was over. And it's a strong country with
a strong military, but it went very
quickly. And now, by the way, uh we have
made a fortune with their oil. And so
have they. They've made more money in
the last eight months than they've made
in the last 10 years. And we're partic
we're really, you know, participating in
the profit.
>> Venezuela, but obviously is a different
kind of a thing. But we're doing
probably almost as well as I I don't
know how you can do better. They have no
navy. They have no air force. It's all
destroyed. Their air force is destroyed.
>> But yet they're talking a big game.
They're big. You know, Iran's foreign
minister said the straight
>> They're not talking big
>> is open to commercial shipping only if
they cooperate with the Iranians.
They're not talking a big game. You know
who's talking a big game? The fake news
media. If you read the New York Times,
you would think that we're losing
militarily. Think of it. They have 159
ships. Everyone is now on the bottom of
the sea. Every one of them is gone. Uh
they had mind droppers. They call them
mind droppers. Nice thing. Who has 22
mind droppers? The mind droppers are all
gone. Now they have what they call fast
boats. You know they are runabouts like
you'd buy for your fantastic son if you
wanted to buy them a nice boat and they
put a machine gun on it. Okay. Uh most
of them are knocked out. We knock them
out just like we knock out the drug
dealers.
>> You like to talk about cards. It seems
like they're playing with a bad deck to
your point. No deck,
>> but they're still playing.
>> No, the only thing they have going is a
fake press. They know how well we're
doing militarily. And then at the
request of a very nice group of people
from Pakistan who are very close to
Iran. I didn't go that final. They said,
"Could you stop? We're going to make a
deal." And we really had the confines of
a deal. No nuclear. They were going to
give us the dust, nuclear dust, all the
everything we wanted. And every time
they make a deal, they the next day it's
like we didn't have that conversation.
And that's taken place about five times.
There's something wrong with them.
Actually, they're crazy. And you know
what? Because of that, they cannot have
a nuclear weapon because
>> the president of China agrees with you
on that. And
>> he agrees with me on that. He agrees
with me that he wants to see it end.
He'd like to see it end. Uh he would
like to help. If he wants help, that's
great. But we don't need help. And you
know the problem with help? When
somebody helps you, they always want
something on the other side. That's the
way help works.
>> Hard to believe, but it was one year ago
today in UAE. Interviewed you and I
asked you about Iran. [snorts]
>> How do you get to a solution there?
>> We'll get 100%.
>> You think so?
>> Well, well, we're going to have a
solution one way or the other. It's
either going to be violent or not
violent. And I far prefer nonviolent.
>> Obviously, you've explained
>> perfect answer. you you've explained why
you did what you did because of the
nuclear threat for Iran.
>> Um
>> but
it's obviously not Venezuela. It's
different.
>> Well, it's different but
>> and but you did say it was going to be
fairly quick. I mean, you said it
numerous times.
>> Venezuela was sending drugs in at a
level that was terrible and they did
something that was a terrible mortal
sin. They emptied their prisons into our
country. Okay, that was terrible. And
that was different. Uh, this one is I
guess you could say worse. It's that was
pretty bad. You don't get much worse.
Emptying your prisons, drug dealers,
murderers into our country. That's
pretty bad. But you could say this is
worse. In this one, they are trying to
make a nuclear weapon. I've stopped it
twice. They would have had it two years
ago. They would have used it already on
Israel and the rest of the Middle East.
Look at all the missiles shot at people
that didn't think they were even
involved. Qatar, Saudi Arabia, UAE. Look
at all I mean Bahrain, uh, Kuwait, they
got all shot at. Nobody thought they
were even involved in this thing. They
would have they would have used a
nuclear weapon on the Middle East. One
thing I'll make clear right now, they
said very specifically, because I deal
with them. I said, "We're taking the
nuclear dust." They said, "You can have
it." I said, "We're going to go get it.
We're not going to let you take it."
They said, "We can't take it. We don't
have the capability of taking it." I
said, "Why?" They said because it was
hit so hard. I mean the mountain
literally collapsed on it. A granite
mountain.
>> So why isn't that good enough?
>> Just so you know. Well, what just Well,
>> I mean, if you want if your goal was to
set back,
>> it is good enough. But you know what?
It's not good enough public relations
wise. Uh it's important, you know, it's
important. Uh it's probably good enough
for a different reason, though. Space
Force, which I created, has got cameras,
nine different cameras in space on that
site. We know everybody that moves
there. We can read the name of a a
person. Uh we can kn if if if his name
is Muhammad something and most of them
are Muhammad. You can guess about 50%
right. Uh we can read his name right on
his tag from space. It's the most
amazing thing. Anybody that goes near
that space, we have it tagged. They
haven't done anything there. And if they
did, we would hit them very hard. So two
days ago in speaking to the Iranians,
they told me it was hit so hard. They
actually said, I must say that there's
only two countries that could get it. US
and China,
>> right?
>> They said us and China that they don't
have the capability of getting it
because it was so obliterated, the term
I used was obliterated. The fake news
said, "Oh, maybe somebody can get it."
They actually said if they wanted to get
it, they couldn't. So, uh, that's not
good enough for me. I want to get it. So
why are we where we are? Did you
underestimate the pain tolerance that
Iran has?
>> I didn't underestimate anything. We hit
them unbelievably hard.
Look,
we left their bridges. We left their
electricity capacity. We can knock that
all out in two days. Two days.
Everything. Uh, we left Car Island other
than I said hit it except for the valves
where the oil comes out because when you
hit that that means you're going to lose
a little oil. But one thing is happening
amazingly. Ships are floating up to
Texas and Louisiana and they're going to
Alaska and they're loading up with oil
like we've never seen before.
>> Americans want to know when it's over
though, right?
>> Yeah. Look, Vietnam lasted 19 years. Uh
Iraq was like 10 years. Korea was 7
years. Uh another one was 14 years.
Another one was 12 years. Another one
was nine years.
We're in there for
two and a half months.
The other thing they talk about, so we
lost tens of thousands of soldiers in
Vietnam. We lost tens of thousands of
soldiers in practically every war.
I've lost and I I I wish we'd lost none
because I know those parents. I spoke to
them. We lost 13 soldiers in two wars.
>> China got three tankers out this week uh
filled with Iranian oil
>> because we allowed that to happen.
>> You did.
>> We allowed that to happen
>> before this trip.
>> Gas prices in America are still high uh
painfully high for
>> they're going to drop like a rocket once
it's over. painfully high though now and
and could be creeping higher than excuse
me lower than Biden and much lower than
people thought they'd be.
>> This inflation number is going up.
You're right. It's much lower than
President Biden's was, but it's going up
under you. Uh the numbers are you can
imagine Democrats and political pundits
uh jumped all over this statement that
you made the other day. You were asked
on the when you were leaving.
>> What extent are American financial
fixations motivating you to make a deal?
>> Not even a little bit. The only thing
that matters when I'm talking about
Iran, they can't have a nuclear weapon.
I don't think about American financial
situation. I don't think about anybody.
I think about one thing. You cannot let
Iran have a nuclear weapon. That's all.
>> That's right. That's a perfect
statement. I'd make it again. You can
[clears throat] imagine how many people
stop the sound bite at
>> I don't think about America financial
situation. So what's your response to
that framework?
>> It's very simple.
>> When people hear me say it, everybody
agrees short-term pain. It's going to be
short-term pain, but the pain is much
less than people thought because people
thought that the oil would go up to
$250. You know, it was $99 yesterday.
$99 a barrel. I thought it might go up
to $200. I was okay with that. Not that
I wanted it, but you cannot let them
have a nuclear weapon. They will use it
on us. They'll start off with Israel,
wipe it out, the Middle East, wipe it
out, it'll go to Europe. You know, they
have a missile that goes to Europe. You
saw that. Okay. They have a missile goes
to Europe. I have done Europe a very big
favor. When you tell somebody you're
gonna have to pay a little more, not
that much more, a little more for gas,
Seline, for a very short period of time
because we want to stop the threat of
being blown to pieces by a lunatic, by a
crazy person. And they are crazy using
nuclear weapons. Everybody says that's
fine. And that question was a fake
question. And they didn't put my full
answer. I totally care. Look, I
inherited high prices and they came in
with a word affordability. my first
press conference two days in and Biden
didn't do press conferences. He'd go for
years without doing because he was
incapable of doing it. He was an
incompetent person. But my first
question was about eggs. Eggs have
quadrupled. What are you going to do? I
said, "Eggs? Tell me about eggs. Tell me
about the problem." Eggs have gone up
four times. They said, "I'll take care
of it." By the way, I did take care of
it. But
they came up with a word because they
are good. They're rotten with policy.
They're horrible politicians in many
cases. They're We have a new name.
They're Democrats. I call them
Democrats. Not Democrats. They're
Democrats.
A lot of low IQ people. You have Ilhan
Omar saying World War 11. She said
world, she was referring to World War
II. She said World War 11. These people
are destroying our country and we have
to stop it. You know, President Xi said
something yesterday. He talked about,
and he wasn't referring to the last 15
months, he talked about America is a
nation in decline. And I said, "You're
right." But he wasn't talking about
because he said, "What you've done in 14
15 months is
a miracle." When you hear Trump voters,
Alex says, "I voted for you three
times." He just he can't handle the
costs. And he's not for this foreign
conflict. I hate it. He's he's not for
the foreign conflict, but Roy in
Pennsylvania, he's a retired farmer. He
can't handle the fuel going up and he's
just he says he's going to come down
very fast.
>> And so, look, I'm disappointed.
>> I'm just telling you when they say to
him,
>> Roy, Alex, we got a problem. We just hit
the highest stock market price ever, by
the way, then when I went in. Now,
again,
>> it's higher
>> with the war. It's higher than it was
when I went in. Think of that. The 401k
is at their alltime high. There are more
people working right now in the United
States of America than at any point ever
in the history of our country.
>> Detroit Free Press, a state that you
won. While champagne flowed on the
trading floor and President Donald Trump
celebrated record highs, pessimism
spread like wildfire outside Wall
Street's doors, straight into the
kitchens of average American families.
There is this sense that,
you know, something is changing. whether
they can hold on and believe that you're
going to get them to No, you
>> I have to do what's right. I said to my
people, we just hit 50,000 on the Dow.
That wasn't supposed to happen for five
or six years. I did it in my first year.
We just hit 7,000 on the S&P. That
wasn't that was even less of a chance of
the than the Dow. We just have we have
it was just announced 401ks are at their
all-time highest that they've ever been.
All these things happened and I said,
"I'm sorry to do this to you, but we
have to stop this
group of very crazy people." Now, those
people are gone. They've been
eliminated. The second group has been
eliminated. And some of the third group
in a way, we've eliminated so many
leaders that it's almost I'm trying to
figure out who the hell are we dealing
with?
>> Who are you dealing with?
>> But well, we're dealing with people that
I think are right, but they're afraid to
make a deal. They don't know how to make
a deal. They've never been put in this
position before.
>> So, you're going to hold out until they
do.
>> Well, I'm going to do what's right. I
have to do what's right.
>> But the straight should be open, right?
>> It should be open. Look, see, to stop
the straight is very easy. All they have
to do is say, "We dropped a mine in the
straight someplace, you know. See, we're
at a little disadvantage, but that's
okay. Uh, the straight will be open.
they will not have a nuclear weapon and
the world will go on and you will see
gasoline prices drop energy prices
generally drop like no don't forget they
have a lot of boats that are loaded up
with oil that are going to bring the oil
out as soon as this is over and I think
it's going to end fast they've been
holding up the world for many many years
with the straight you know they've used
this many many times they said we'll
close the straight they've closed it in
the past they use it as a weapon They're
not using it as a weapon with me. And
what they did, and actually what
President Xi said last night, sort of
smiling about it, he said, "Well, they
close us rate and then you close them."
>> But you think they're going to
capitulate sometime soon?
>> Yeah. Oh, sure.
>> I have no doubt.
>> Mr. President, stand by if you would.
Special report from Beijing with the
president of the United States continues
after this.
>> Be sure to like and subscribe for all
the Fox News latest on YouTube and catch
full shows streaming now on Fox One.